<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>I am Jolene - Build up your own blog</title><link href="https://joleneyu.github.io/i-am-jolene/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://joleneyu.github.io/i-am-jolene/feeds/build-up-your-own-blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://joleneyu.github.io/i-am-jolene/</id><updated>2021-08-04T17:05:00+10:00</updated><entry><title>Side Project - Build Personal Blog I</title><link href="https://joleneyu.github.io/i-am-jolene/side-project-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-26T14:04:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-08-04T17:05:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Jolene Yu</name></author><id>tag:joleneyu.github.io,2021-07-26:/i-am-jolene/side-project-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The website you are browsing at is my first side project which leveraged with static site generator - Pelican. This blog is about initial steps of how to install Pelican and some lesson-learned while I was building up mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelican is powered by python and requires no database or server-side logic …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The website you are browsing at is my first side project which leveraged with static site generator - Pelican. This blog is about initial steps of how to install Pelican and some lesson-learned while I was building up mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelican is powered by python and requires no database or server-side logic which is easier for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Before start:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get python, pip3, git installed  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a Pelican theme you like (here is the one I used https://github.com/nairobilug/pelican-alchemy)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new repository at GitHub or any other git repository management for this project. (Strongly recommend to use GitHub, because this tutorial has further setups for GitHub Pages and GitHub Actions) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When you are ready with these prerequisites, let's jump to how to kickstart a website.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install pelican  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ pip install pelican&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Markdown if you plan on using Markdown as a markup format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ pip install Markdown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a directory to house the site content and configuration files, which can be located any place you prefer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ mkdir ~/Desktop/yoursitename&lt;br&gt;
$ cd ~/Desktop/yoursitename&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the pelican-quickstart command, which will ask some questions about your site (Those settings can be changed anytime after in the configuration file, so don't worry too much here!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ pelican-quickstart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the theme installtion instruction, which is avaiable in the GitHub repository README.md, and add the theme folder as a submodule&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ mkdir themes&lt;br&gt;
$ git submodule add https://github.com/nairobilug/pelican-alchemy themes/pelican-alchemy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to generate and serve your site locally at http://localhost:8000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$ make devserver  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this tutorial, you should see a locally served template site like this! Don't worry if your site is missing some images or menu settings, we can figure those things out later!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't forget to use git to snyc your local repository with remote one. You can always fall back to the old version if you messed up some settings later.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="This one is just a literal element" src="https://joleneyu.github.io/i-am-jolene/images/default.png" data-action="zoom" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lesson-Learned Time:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tutorial looks quite straight-forward, but sometimes when I don't understand something 100%, I choose to look for more information on google which is time-consuming. I advise just to try it out. Hit a command and see what terminal says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are not sure about some setting, make smaller changes instead of multiple changes at same time. Make steps smaller, make identify problems quicker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use .gitignore wisely. I'm using VS code as my code editor, and it showed I have some uncommit/unstaged changes even if I didn't change anything. I found out .DS_Store was the problem. It's safe to untrack this file. I saved a lot of effort for context switching after I put it to .gitignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submoudle is another repository from the site repository, it needs to sync seperately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="Build up your own blog"></category><category term="pelican"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="git"></category></entry></feed>